Guide to the Amos L. Williams Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Amos Loomis Williams papers
1830-1888
MS 1081
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
Notebooks, financial records, and miscellanea of Amos L. Williams, a physician in Brookfield, Connecticut. Includes notes on lectures of Eli Ives, William Tully, and others.
Williams, Amos Loomis, 1811-1896
Biographical / Historical
Amos L. Williams, physician, was born on January 7, 1811, in Lebanon, Connecticut. Williams received diplomas from Jefferson Medical School, Philadelphia and Yale Medical School, New Haven. He represented the town of Brookfield, Connecticut, at the state legislature in 1883 and served the town as medical examiner, postmaster, and registrar. His professional life in Brookfield extended over sixty-three years. He died on April 16, 1896, in Brookfield Center, Connecticut.
Scope and Contents
Notebooks, financial records, and miscellanea of Amos L. Williams, a physician in Brookfield, Connecticut. Includes notes on lectures of Eli Ives, William Tully, and others.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Medical fees; Medical students -- Connecticut; Medicine; Physicians -- Finance, Personal; Brookfield (Conn.); Connecticut; Account books; Physicians; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869; Ives, Eli, 1779-1861; Revere, John, 1787-1847; Tully, William, 1785-1859; Williams, Amos Loomis, 1811-1896; Williams, Sarah Juliette Holley; Jefferson Medical College; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Inventory
  - Sarah Juliette (Holley) Williams (1811-1888)
    - Autograph album, 1830-1834 (Box 1)
    - Commonplace book, 1834-1878 (Box 1)
  - Amos L. Williams (1811-1896)
    - Notebooks on medical lectures (Box 1)
    - Dr. Eli Ives, Yale Medical School, 1831 (Box 2)
    - Dr. William Tully, Yale Medical School, 1831-1832 (Box 2)
    - Dr. John Revere, Jefferson Medical College, [1840] (Box 2)
    - Dr. Robley Dunglison, Jefferson Medical College, [1840] (Box 2)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 2)
    - Expense book, 1846-1860 (Box 2)
    - Expense book, 1860-1887 (Box 2)
    - Ledger of medical accounts, 1851-1888 (Box 2)
    - Address given at a community dinner, undated (Box 2)
    - Day books of medical accounts (Box 2)
    - 1844-1857 (Box 3)
    - 1852-1857 (Box 3)
    - 1872-1880 (Box 3)
    - 1881-1886 (Box 3)